测试更一般流程的示例
Testing the example of a more general process
称为验证，它是关于发现问题
called validation, which is about uncovering problems
希望能增加你的信心
in your program and hopefully increasing your confidence
这是正确的。
that it's correct.
其他类型的验证包括形式推理，
Some other kinds of validation include formal reasoning,
也被称为验证，其中
which is also called verification, where
你所做的是试图建立一个正式的证据
what you're doing is trying to construct a formal proof
程序是正确的。
that the program is correct.
这可能是非常乏味的手工操作，特别是
This can be very tedious to do by hand, particularly
有更大的程序。
with larger programs.
验证的自动化工具支持即将到来，
Automated tool support for verification is coming,
但它仍然是一个活跃的研究领域，
but it's still an active area of research,
但你可能还是会发现那些关键的小碎片
but you may still find that small, crucial pieces
一个程序的
of a program might be formally verified
就像操作系统调度器
like an operating system scheduler
或者字节码解释器甚至文件
or a bytecode interpreter or even the file
操作系统中的系统。
system in an operating system.
第二种验证是代码检查
The second kind of validation is code review
我们已经在之前的阅读中讨论过了。
and we've already talked about that in a previous reading.
基本上，代码审查就是让其他人仔细阅读
Basically code review is having somebody else carefully read
你的代码，随便想想，
your code, think about it informally,
试着去寻找虫子。
and try to look for bugs.
就像有人校对
It's a lot like having somebody proofread
你写的一篇文章。
an essay that you've written.
第三种验证我们
The third kind of validation we're
我们要谈谈今天，这是考验。
going to talk about the day, which is testing.
测试基本上是运行程序，并且非常小心
Testing is basically running the program and very carefully
选择输入并检查其是否正确。
selected inputs and checking that it does the right thing.
现在有一个警告——即使是最好的验证，
Now a note of warning-- even with the very best validation,
这三种技术
all three of these techniques, it's
在软件方面很难达到完美的质量。
very hard to achieve perfect quality in software.
你永远也找不到所有的虫子。
You're never going to find all the bugs.
一些研究——一些残余缺陷率，
Some studies here-- some residual defect rates,
这是软件运行后遗留的错误数
that is the number of bugs left over after the software has
作为代码行数的函数提供
shipped as a function of the number of lines of code
在那个软件里。
in that software.
对于典型的行业实践，通常使用测试
For typical industry practices, usually using testing
在代码评审中，最终会出现1到10个错误
in code review, you end up with 1 to 10 bugs
每1000行代码。
per 1,000 lines of code.
像你这样的高质量验证
With very high quality validation like you
可能在库代码中找到，例如，
might find in library code, for example,
你可以做的比那好10倍
you can do about 10 times better than that and with very
最佳任务关键型验证，
best mission critical kinds of validation,
你还可以再做10次。
you might do another 10 times better than that.
但结果是你永远不会去
But the result is you're never going
除掉所有的虫子
to get rid of all the bugs and this
如果你
can be very discouraging if you're
建立一个非常大的系统。
building a very large system.
所以如果你有一百万行——典型的行业代码
So if you ship a million lines-- typical industry code, which
是目前典型的大型桌面应用程序
is typical large desktop application these days-- at one
每1000行代码有一个bug，意思是
bug per 1,000 lines of code, it means
你所发布的代码中有1000个bug
you've got 1,000 bugs in the code that you've shipped
随着时间的推移你会逐渐发现
and you're going to gradually discover those over time
当用户遇到他们时。
as users run into them.
不幸的是，软件测试比
Unfortunately, software testing is harder than
其他形式的工程测试。
testing in other forms of engineering.
详尽的测试，即尝试所有可能的输入
Exhaustive testing, that is trying all possible inputs
对于一个软件来说，往往是完全不可行的
to a piece of software, tends to be completely infeasible
即使你想的是一个简单的水平
even if you're thinking about something as simple as a level
涉及两个32位输入的乘法运算。
multiply operation involving two 32-bit inputs.
好吧，32个可能值中有两个
Well, there's two to the 32 possible values
对于a，b有2到32个可能值。
for a, there's two to the 32 possible values for b.
所以对于a和b对，有2到64个可能的测试
So for the pair a and b, there is 2 to the 64 possible test
如果你想的话你必须尝试的案例
cases that you would have to try if you wanted
做详尽的测试
to do exhaustive testing and that's more the number of atoms
在宇宙中。
in the universe.
另一种测试是随机测试
Another kind of testing is haphazard testing
你经常在新手和业余爱好者中看到这种情况
and you often see this with novices and amateurs
那些正在学习编程的人
and people who are just learning to program, where you just
向它抛出一些输入，看看它是否
throw some inputs at it and see if it does
正确的事情，你没有
the right thing, where you haven't
做了任何系统的尝试来仔细选择这些输入。
made any systematic attempt to choose those inputs carefully.
除非程序真的
That's not likely to find bugs unless the program is really
它并不能增加我们的信心
buggy and it really doesn't increase our confidence
程序是正确的，所以我们没有
that the program is correct, so we're not
我们来谈谈随机测试。
going to talk about haphazard testing.
我们不会真的谈论随机或统计
We're not really going to talk about random or statistical
也在测试。
testing either.
这是一种非常常用的技术
This is a very common technique used
其他工程学科--
in other kinds of engineering disciplines--
制造业和土木工程。
in manufacturing and civil engineering.
你要做的是随机抽取一个小样本，
What you do is you pick a small, random sample-- let's say,
产品的，硬盘的
of the product, of the hard drives coming off
你的生产线——测试它们，然后推断
of your manufacturing line-- test them, and then infer
整批的错误率
the bug rate for the entire lot that's
从你的生产基地出来
coming out of your production based
关于那些测试的结果。
on the results of those testing.
现在在物理工程领域
Now in physical engineering, there's
你可以用很多技巧来加速这种测试。
lots of tricks you can use to speed up this kind of testing.
你制造的机器会打开和关闭
You build machines that are going to open and close
你的冰箱每天1000次而不是通常的10次
your refrigerator 1,000 times in a day instead of the usual 10
他们的冰箱可能要花上好几年的时间
years that it might take for their fridge
多次开放。
to be opened many times.
而这些加速会导致可预见的已知故障
And those speed ups give predictable, known failure
但问题是
rates, but the problem is that they
假设存在某种连续性
assume that there is some continuity
或是在可能的虫子空间中的一致性
or uniformity across the space of possible bugs
在物质世界里是这样的，
and that's true in the physical world,
但在软件上却不是这样。
but it's not true in software.
软件往往会不连续地变化
Software tends to vary discontinuously-- there's
一个突然失败而不是逐渐失败的地方
an abrupt place where it fails rather than gradually failing
当它越来越接近
as it gets closer and closer to the point where
他们的窃听器存在，它会突然
their bug exists, it'll just suddenly
在某个边界点失败。
fail at some single boundary point.
有一些著名的bug，比如奔腾分区bug
There are some famous bugs like the Pentium division bug
影响了90亿分之一的浮点数
that affected one in 9 billion floating point divides
也没有什么模式对它产生影响。
and there wasn't much pattern to which ones it effected.
类似的堆栈溢出错误，out
Similarly stack overflow errors, out
内存错误，数值溢出
of memory errors, numeric overflow
bug——当软件命中时，这些bug往往会突然发生
bugs-- these tend to happen abruptly when the software hits
一些它不期望的而且总是
some input that it doesn't expect and always
以同样的方式，而不是一些概率变化
in the same way, not with some probabilistic variation
这样我们就可以通过随机抽样找到它。
that would allow us to find it with random sampling.
它们也不会逐渐显现出来
And they also tend not to gradually show
当他们接近那一点时失败的证据。
evidence of failure as they're approaching that point.
在那之前他们一直都很好
They work fine all the way up until that one
会导致失败的90亿分之一。
in 9 billion division that will cause failure.
所以随机测试有时是有用的，
So random testing is sometimes useful,
但坦率地说，统计样本并非如此
but frankly statistical samples are not that
在软件测试中很有用。
useful in software testing.
所以我们要做的是仔细选择我们的测试用例
So what we have to do instead is choose our test cases carefully
系统性的，下一步我们要做的
and systematically and the next thing we're going to do
就是想办法做到这一点。
is look at a way to do that.